[Music]
in 2025 release Wave 1 we are releasing
a really big change or update to the
manufacturing
analytics um in this video I will show
you what we have done in the powerbi app
and there's also a different um video
that is only um about the modernization
of the Legacy reports in
manufacturing so here we're going to
talk about uh updated reports in the
powerbi app note that all of this is
coming in version
26.1 new reports surfacing in the
powerbi app for manufacturing and uh and
then some learn more links if you want
to dive into uh the specifics of
analytics for
manufacturing but before we do that that
we have some so had some guiding themes
of our investment in updating the
powerbi app for this release wave and
that consists of three pillars we took a
lot of feedback from subject matter
experts in the partner Community um in
within manufacturing and uh and then we
incorporated that into the existing app
second we have uh this vision of
modernizing in the Legacy reports in in
manufacturing and simply making as much
of the analytical analytical power in
these old reports available in power
pi and then we couldn't help ourselves
also adding some of the things where
powerbi really shines so we added a
report that give you a Gant
visualization of your pro production
order routing lines so um let's dive
into first um the first part which is
updated reports in the powerbi app so
let's first take a look at some of the
reports that we updated in the
manufacturing power PI app the first is
the work center load report here you can
see the original version from last
semester and here you can see the
updated
report another example is expected
capacity
need where uh the previous one here is
in the left
and uh the new version here is on the
right and I'll demo all three so that
you get a closer look the final one I
want to show you is finished production
order breakdown again you can see uh the
original version here on the left and
the current version now so let's dive
into powerbi and just uh explore these
three updated reports so the reworked
work center report um or load report is
first of all showing a better
visualization across your work centers
here um with color scheme of allocated
time and also how much is then available
after you have put in orders the new
design is also um much easier if you
have multiple work centers so that um it
it simply fits the screen better and
then we decided to put in a detailed um
statistics report below here so that you
can um whenever you pick a single work
center here you can then um dive into
the details in the
table the updated expected capacity need
report have a couple of enhancements
first of all you can see that the report
now both shows analytics or insights by
work center and also show it by Machine
Center and the second enhancement is
that the details here is not only on the
order but you can actually go down to
the order line level as
well the final updated report I want to
show you here is the finished production
order breakdown this uh new version of
the report um shows first of all kpi but
there's also a new focus on costs and
the breakdown of cost cost by production
order here you can see the actual costs
uh the actual capacity overhead cost the
cost Associated to overhead um the
actual overhead cost and so on so um
hopefully that gives you a better way to
to look at your production orders uh
with that view in mind um breaking down
the cost for them we also added a lot of
new reports some of them under not as
visually appealing as what you maybe see
in the sales app or other apps and
that's because we Mig graded or
replicated a lot of the statistical
reports from Legacy power um
manufacturing so that's why they're very
table like in at least in the first
version here we might change that in a
later release Here you see the work
center statistics report and note that
you can see capacity in minutes uh that
is something that that you can change
but you have to get access to the
powerbi um file for that and uh let's
see if we can make that
happen the second report is a machine
Center statistics very similar um to the
other one except this shows you also
statistics on scrap um and uh let me
actually just show you that so here is
the report live you have a lot of a lot
of numbers here so many that I even need
to scroll to the right here uh to see
things um or measures kpi such as
allocated time Center output scrap scrap
percentage uh stop time and so on so um
this machine Center statistics should
give you everything you need to go down
on that detail in your
tion the final report I will demo today
there are actually many more is the
production order rounding lines Gant
chart so with this report um you can
either look at your production order
lines or routing lines in a visual way
here whenever you interact with the
visual Parts the table part will follow
along if you think this particular
visual is too small you can always make
it uh bigger in the focus mode here and
then uh you can interact with the
different parts uh or sorry different
orders and see the routing lines over
this timeline this is not on live data
this is the data that has been refreshed
in the powerbi uh report so um so you
might also want have to have more live
versions of this but we U we we still
thought it would be interesting to see
the routing line in a g chart in the
report so let us know what you think and
and how how you can use this in your
daily operations now this was just a
sneak peek into the enhanced powerbi app
for manufacturing that we ship in
version
26.1 you might have noticed that I am
not demoing in the embedded experience
this is because right now and when we
record this that part we're still
finishing up so that's why I'm I'm
showing the raw pay powerbi
um in this updated app you can see here
on the screen that we have updated uh
these six reports um we will also likely
deprecate uh these two current
utilization and historical
utilization likely just hide them in in
this version and then remove them in a
later one and then you get new reports I
you saw work center statistics machine
load um a few these uh but we also and
at the routing um again there are also
task uh a task list um drill through
that apparently I have twice here on the
list so sorry about that um so try it
out try see how it works for you give us
feedback if we need to do some
adjustments we'll happy to do that uh to
make this um really useful for your
manufacturing business
if you're interested in learning more
about analytics in the manufacturing
area the easiest way I find is simply to
have this AKA Link
aka.ms slbc Manufacturing analytics and
let's just uh go there and see what that
is all about and then um you are off for
this video and can go and learn some
other things so the manufacturing
analytics landing page follow the same
structure as all the other functional
areas I'll just scroll down a little
here um so we are under manufacturing
and here you have both the documentation
for the powerbi app each of the pages
have their own documentation page but
you also here have an overview of
production uh reports uh here both um
the Legacy ones uh the ones that will
likely be started a in this release wave
and a lot of the new reports that if you
want to see what that's about you need
to go and watch the the other video on
what's new in manufacturing analytics
for with reporting aspects so with that
I wish you a great launch event I hope
you learned something here and also
we'll continue learning in the other
sessions thank you